Alexander Hollaender Papers 1955-1974 Mss.B.H717
American Philosophical Society
- Alexander Hollaender Papers, 1955-1974; 4 lin. feet
  - National Academy of Sciences. Committee on the Genetic Effects of Atomic Radiation, 1955-1962; 30 folders (Box 5)
    - Folder 4, 1956; 2 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 5, 1956; 4 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 6, 1956; 2 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 7, 1956-1957; 2 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 8, 1956-1957; 2 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 9, 1957; 2 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 10, 1957-1958; 6 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 11, 1959; 2 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 12, 1959; 1 item (Box 5)
    - Folder 13, 1959; 12 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 14, 1959; 3 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 15, 1959; 1 item (Box 5)
    - Folder 16, 1959; 6 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 17, 1959; 3 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 18, 1959; 1 item (Box 5)
    - Folder 19, 1959; 2 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 20, 1959; 4 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 21, 1959; 3 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 22, 1960; 1 item (Box 5)
    - Folder 23, 1960; 3 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 24, 1960; 9 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 25, 1960; 2 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 26, 1960; 2 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 27, 1960; 1 item (Box 5)
    - Folder 28, 1960; 7 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 29, 1962; 3 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 30, 1962; 4 items (Box 5)
  - National Research Council, 1966-1967; 2 folders (Box 5)
    Conferences and symposia; Genetics; National Research Council
    - Folder 1, 1966-1967; 9 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 2, 1967; 8 items (Box 5)
  - National Science Foundation, 1959 January 27; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Neel, James V., 1956-1957; 10 items (Box 5)
  - Advanced Study Institute Program, 1963; 1 item; North Atlantic Treaty Organization (Box 5)
  - Nowell, Peter C., 1965 April 20; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Nuclear Development Corporation, 1958 August 23; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Oakberg, E. F., 1965 April 21; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Oliver and Boyd, LTD., 1957; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Pappenheimer, A. M., jr., 1957 March 20; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Pavanello, R., 1971 June 21; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Pauling, Linus, 1957-1958; 5 items (Box 5)
  - Peacock, W. J. (Box 5)
    General note
    See: International Conference on Replication.....
  - Pergamon Press Limited, 1958; 5 items (Box 5)
  - Perutz, M. F., 1963; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Picker, Harvey, 1957; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Plaut, Mlle., 1957; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Plough, H. H., 1956 July 2; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Ray, Lloyd A., 1956; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Rizki, T. M., 1970; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Radiation Hazards in the Field of Pediatrics, n.d.; 1 item; Robinow, Meinhard; Silverman, Frederic N. (Box 5)
  - Meeting, Genetic Intervention in Humans, 1966; 3 items; Rockefeller University. (Box 5)
  - Rogers, Stanfield, 1966 May 17; 1 item (Box 5)
  - The Rejection of the WHO Research Center, 1967; 1 item; Rose, Hilary (Box 5)
  - Rotblat, J., 1963 August 26; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Russell, William Lawson, 1958-1965; 6 items (Box 5)
  - Sallmann, Ludwig von, 1965 April 21; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Schambra, Philip E., 1965 April 30; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Science Information Service, 1957-1959; 8 items (Box 5)
  - Searle, A. G., 1965 April 22; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Sella, Francesco, 1964-1870; 10 items (Box 5)
  - Sheeks, Robert B., 1966-1967; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Setlow, Richard Burton, n.d.; 1 item (Box 5)
  - The Potential Contribution of Atomic Energy to Development in Agriculture and Related Industries, 1958; 1 item; Silow, R. A. (Box 5)
  - Simoes, Luiz Carlos Gomes, 1973 September 27; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Slaughter, Eileen J., 1957 February 14; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Sobels, F. H., 1970 October 20; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Stansly, Philip G., 1973; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Stern, Curt, 1957; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Stevenson, A. C., 1956; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Folder 1, 1956; 11 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 2, 1956; 9 items (Box 5)
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 1957 September 23; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Sturtevant, A. H., 1957; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Symposium on Genetics in Medical Research, 1958; 15 items (Box 5)
  - Taylor, Lauriston, 1956 October 3; 1 item (Box 6)
  - Tobias, Cornelius A., 1965; 2 items (Box 6)
  - Tolbert, N. Edward, 1957 March 28; 1 item (Box 6)
  - Totter, John, 1970; 3 items (Box 6)
  - United Nations. General Assembly. Scientific Committee on the Effects of Atomic Radiation, 1956-1969; 39 folder (Box 6)
    - Folder 1, 1956; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 2, 1956; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 3, 1956; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 4, 1956 October 25; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 5, 1957; 2 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 6, 1957; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 7, 1957; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 8, 1957; 3 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 9, 1957 October 31; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 10, 1957; 2 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 11, 1957; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 12, 1957; 2 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 13, 1957; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 14, 1957; 7 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 15, 1957; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 16, 1957; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 17, 1957; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 18, 1957; 2 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 19, 1957; 7 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 20, 1957; 2 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 21, 1957; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 22, 1957; 4 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 23, 1958 July 23; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 24, 1958; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 25, 1958 July 23; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 26, 1958 July 23; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 27, 1958 July 23; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 28, 1958 July 23; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 29, 1958; 6 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 30, 1959 April 10; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 31, 1960; 2 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 32, 1964 June 5; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 33, 1964 June 8; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 34, 1964 June 8; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Folder 35, 1964; 2 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 36, 1964 June 29; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 37, 1964; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 38, 1969 January 23; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 39, 1969 January 23; 1 item (Box 7)
  - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1959; 3 items (Box 7)
  - United States. Dept. of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1973-1974; 5 items (Box 7)
  - Upton, Arthur Canfield, 1962-1964; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Folder 1, 1962; 2 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1964; 4 items (Box 7)
  - Wallace, Bruce, 1956 October 11; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Warren, Shields, 1956-1957; 5 items (Box 7)
  - Weaver, Warren, 1955-1957; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Folder 1, 1955-1957; 8 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1956; 5 items (Box 7)
  - Weinberg, Alvin M., 1964-1965; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Weiss, Charles, 1970 March 20; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Westergaard, Mogens, 1956; 3 items (Box 7)
  - White, Virginia P., 1956; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Winters, C. E., 1958 August 6; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Wolff, Sheldon, 1967-1969; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Workshop Conference on Space Radiation Biology, 1964-1965; 6 items (Box 7)
  - World Health Organization, 1956-1965; 5 folders (Box 7)
    Committee activities; Muller, Hermann Joseph; Neel, James V.; Publication; Radiation genetics; World Health Organization, United Nations
    - Folder 1, 1956; 15 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1956-1957; 20 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 3, 1958; 2 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 4, 1960; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 5, 1965; 12 items (Box 7)
  - Report, 1963; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Report, 1962; 2 items (Box 7)
  - A Proposal for the WHO Drug Reaction System, 1965; 3 items (Box 7)
  - World Health Organization. International Health and Biomedical Research, 1963-1964; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Folder 1, 1963 December 6; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1963-1964; 3 items (Box 7)
  - World Health Organization. International Laboratory of Molecular Biology, 1964; 3 items (Box 7)
  - World Health Organization. Proposal for Research Center, 1963-1966; 24 folders (Box 7)
    Laboratory techniques, equipment; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; World Health Organization, United Nations
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 11 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 6 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 2 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 4, 1963 March 14-16; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 5, 1963 March 18; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 6, 1963 March 18; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 7, 1963 March 18; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 8, 1963 June 10; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 9, 1963 June 26; 4 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 10, 1963 July 24; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 11, 1963 August 7; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 12, 1963 August 7; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 13, 1964 March 25; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 14, 1964; 2 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 15, 1964; 3 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 16, 1964; 4 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 17, n.d.; 2 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 18, 1964; 2 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 19, 1964; 2 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 20, 1965; 6 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 21, 1965 April; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 22, 1965 August 2-7; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 23, 1965 August 2-7; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 24, 1966 October 31; 1 item (Box 8)
  - World Health Organization. Proposal for a European Organization of Fundamental Biology, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 2 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 1 item (Box 8)
  - World Health Organization. Special Research Development, 1963; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Folder 1, 1963; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 2, 1963; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 3, 1963; 1 item (Box 8)
  - World Health Organization. Study Group on the Effect of Radiation on Human Genetics, 1955-1956; 18 folders (Box 8)
    Conferences and symposia; Human genetics; Radiation genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; World Health Organization, United Nations
    - Folder 1, 1955-1956; 5 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 2, 1956; 6 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 3, 1956; 2 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 4, 1956; 4 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 5, 1956; 10 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 6, 1956; 3 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 7, 1956; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 8, 1956 August 7-11; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 9, 1956 August 7-11; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 10, 1956 August 7-11; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 11, 1956 August 7-11; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 12, 1956 August 7-11; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 13, 1956 August 7-11; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 14, 1956 August 7-11; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 15, 1956; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 16, 1956; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 17, 1956; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Folder 18, 1956; 1 item (Box 8)
  - World Health Organization. Study Group on the Effect of Radiation on Human Genetics. Papers, 1956; 7 folders (Box 8)
    - Folder 1, 1956; 2 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 2, 1956; 2 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 3, 1956; 3 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 4, 1956; 2 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 5, 1956; 3 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 6, 1956; 3 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 7, 1956; 4 items (Box 8)
  - Zelle, Max R., 1958 July 3; 1 item (Box 8)